

UBEYDULLAH KELEŞ



I am an AI enthusiast with a background in retail and e-commerce. Between 2008 and 2022, I worked in several fields and experienced different approaches to work and life. My previous job titles include; market management specialist (one year), retail store manager (eight years), start-up owner (three years), and business analyst (half a year). Beginning in 2021, I started learning **Python**, **data analysis**, and **artificial intelligence**. As part of my learning journey, I got accepted to Google Developers ML Bootcamp Turkey 2022 in July. I will graduate from the boot camp in November with a TensorFlow Developer Certificate. By the end of the boot camp, I will have studied and practiced deep learning for 4.5 months. My current goal is to start working at a company doing exciting data-related work. I am **thorough** and bring a **spirited commitment** to my work. I lived outside Turkey for about a year. Reading general science, learning French, and practising yoga are some of the fun things that I do outside work. I am an **essentialist** at heart.



WORK EXPERIENCE

03/2022 – 08/2022 İstanbul, Turkey

Business analyst Veripark

I worked as a business analyst at Veripark from March to August 2022 as part of a team comprising 15 members. We built and maintained the online banking platform for our foreign client in the financial sector. I was the only analyst in the unit; others worked as software developers and QA specialists. The work was tech-intense, challenging, and fun! I quit my job at Veripark to fully commit to learning AI.

02/2019 – 05/2022 Istanbul, Turkey

Founder Kolay Çerçeve (www.kolaycerceve.com)

- Bootstrapped 200k+ TL and developed brand identity, marketing strategy, and manufacturing processes as the founder of Turkey's first and only **photo** printing and custom framing e-commerce business,
- Grew sales to more than **700 successfully fulfilled orders** from across Turkey within three years, expanded Instagram audience base to 4.5k+ organic followers, and maintained 5-star company rating on Google,
- Initiated and managed relationships with a network of 10 suppliers, nine
 artists, and 10+ designers, creative agencies, and developers, and developed
 strategic partnerships to serve as printing supplier to three e-commerce
 companies in Turkey,
- Managed company website from development to daily maintenance, including conducting user testing and addressing technical issues, optimizing Google Ads campaigns, and analyzing website usage and sales reports,
- Collaborated with UI/UX designer to create company website, marketing and packaging material and website visuals.

10/2021 - 02/2022

Co-founder Pebbles

- Co-founded boutique **data science agency** on Upwork specializing in statistical analysis and natural language processing,
- Defined technical scope for services and drafted 40+ proposals for potential clients.
- Liaised between UK-based client and technical partner to analyze client needs and create natural language processing-based taxonomy of data science roles as first project in January 2022, delivered to full satisfaction of client.

03/2012 - 03/2020

Store manager and brand creator Amant Turc

- Transformed traditional family-owned fine art business into Turkey's first contemporary art print shop specializing in digital illustration, photography, and custom printing and framing,
- Generated repeat business through exceptional customer service and grew a
 loyal customer base of locals, expats, and international visitors, establishing
 Amant Turc as a focal point for accessible art lovers and the digital arts
 community,
- Recruited 40+ Turkish and international artists and negotiated terms of art sales,
- Managed procurement, inventory, budget and accounting, artist collaboration, and customer engagement,
- Oversaw complete renovation of space in historical building—from interior design to storefront and product display—to highlight original architectural features and align physical space with brand identity.

08/2008 - 09/2009

Market Management Specialist Eureko Sigorta

- Joined insurance company as management trainee,
- Led customer segmentation project which consisted of seven members from various departments,
- Prepared monthly sales KPIs and industry benchmarking reports and shared with management.

08/2007 - 11/2007

International Marketing Intern Arçelik A.Ş.

 Analyzed international sales and advertising data, created reports for department manager.



EDUCATION

09/2011 - 09/2012

Psychology Istanbul Şehir University

 Took eight courses ranging from critical thinking to understanding science and technology to understanding politics and economy.

09/2003 - 03/2008

B.S. Industrial Engineering | 3.25/4.00 Yıldız Technical University



1999 - 2003

Sciences | 4.37/5.00 **Vefa High School**



SKILLS AND TOOLS

- DIGITAL PRODUCT DEVELOPMENT

Business Analysis

••••

Assurance ••••

Software Quality

Usability Testing

UI/UX Design ••••

Project Lifecycle Management

••••

Trello

Bitbucket

••000

- E-COMMERCE MANAGEMENT

Customer Experience

00000

Google Ads ••••

Shopify •••• **Digital Advertising**

••••

Google Analytics

0000

- ANALYTICS

MS Excel ••••

Python ••000 Data Analysis •0000

SQL

•0000

Machine Learning / AI

•0000

- DESIGN TOOLS

Adobe Photoshop

Adobe Illustrator

•0000

•0000

- LANGUAGES

Turkish **Native**

English C2

French **A1**

COURSES I AM TAKING AS OF JULY 2022



Google Developers ML Bootcamp Turkey 2022



100 Days of Code: The Complete Python Bootcamp by Dr. Angela Yu



Programming for Data Science and Python (Nanodegree)



Product Management 101 by Todd Birzer



12/2021

Python for Data Science and Machine Learning Bootcamp Jose Portilla

https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-6110174a-59af-4d5c-8951-7a248756d326/



SUPERPOWERS

Modest

Essentialist

Resilient

Big picture obsessed

Conceptual thinker

Super-analytical



SOCIAL MEDIA





my Linkedin profile

my Goodreads profile